Guide to the Whitman College Tau Kappa Epsilon records 1930-2017
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Whitman College Tau Kappa Epsilon records
1930-2017
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
WCA057
1.75 linear feet 3 boxes
The Alpha Eta chapter of Tau Kappa Epsilon was chartered in 1934 as one of Whitman's national greek groups. The collection consists of legal documents, correspondence, memorabilia, publications, alumni and student records related to this fraternity.
Collection is open for research.
Tau Kappa Epsilon is an international Greek Letter fraternity that was established at Illinois Wesleyan University in 1899. The Whitman College Chapter, known as Alpha Eta, was chartered from local fraternity, Alpha Omicron Kappa in 1930. Alpha Omicron Kappa had existed since 1925 and was intended to be made into a chapter of Sigma Alpha Epsilon (the fraternity Whitman president Stephen B. Penrose once belonged to), but was deemed too small. Tau Kappa Epsilon, which was rapidly expanding at the time, was happy to absorb the organization.
The collection consists of legal documents, correspondence, memorabilia, publications, alumni and student records related to the Alpha Eta chapter of Tau Kappa Epsilon.
Tau Kappa Epsilon. Alpha Eta Chapter
Greek letter societies; Whitman College--History
Colleges and Universities
- "Alpha Theta News", 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Alumni Times of Alpha Theta", 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "A-T-EKE" newsletter, 1937-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- "The Black Book of Tau Kappa Epsilon", 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Constitution, by-laws and traditions, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1930-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7-11)
- Financial records, 1941-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
- "A History of Alpha Theta Chapter of Tau Kappa Epsilon Fraternity", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Meeting minutes: Wartime planning, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Membership directory, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Membership registers, 1945-1955 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
- Newspaper articles, 1943-2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Officer and adviser appointments, 1946-1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Photographs, 1949, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
- Social events and promotional materials, 1938-1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- "Teke Life" magazine, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "The Teke Sing Fraters Sing Songbook", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Dance and event programs, 1930-1949 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Photograph: Composite, 2016-2017 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook, 1942 (Box 3, Object 1)